생각해봤는데, 이제 에마한테
첫 과자를 줘도 될 것 같아
You know, I'm thinking about letting Emma have her first cookie.
First cookie? She has cookies all the time.
첫 과자라고?
과자라면 항상 먹고 있잖아.
난 한 번도 에마한테 과자를 준 적이 없는데..
혹시 준거야?
I've never given her a cookie.
Have you?
No.
아니.
그리고 확실히 해 두자면
캔에 든 설탕을 준 적도 없어.
And for the record I've also never given her frosting from a can.
Hey, Rach. The adoption agency needs letters of recommendation
레이첼, 입양 에이젼시에서 추천서가
필요하다는데 혹시 네가 써줄 수 있어?
and we were wondering if you'd write one for us.
- 그럼! 영광이야.
- 고마워
Of course! I'll be honored / Thanks
Thank you.
I think there's been an oversight.
혹시 너희 뭔가 못보고 지나친게 있지 않니?
조이, 물론 너한테 부탁할 수도
있었지만, 우린 단지 네가 관심이
없을 거라고 생각한것 뿐이야.
Joey, we would have asked you.
We just thought you wouldn't be interested
Yeah, it's just that we don't think of you as
really being so much with the words
그래, 그냥 우리가 보기에 니가..
그렇게 말주변이 있다고 생각하진 않았으니까.
What? Wait-hey. Hey Ho Hey
뭐라고? 어이, 뭐야~ 이런, 야!!
Clearly we were wrong.
확실히 말주변이 없는 건 아니네.
Look, I've got a lot of nice stuff to say about you guys, okay?
나도 너희들에 관해서라면
괜찮은 할 말이 많다구. 그렇잖아?
난 너희가 얼마나 아이를
갖고 싶어 하는 지도 알고
I know how much you want to have a baby
and I would love to help you get one.
기꺼이 도와주고 싶단 말야.
-You know what? Then, Joey, we want you to do it
-Thank you
그렇다면 조이, 네가 추천서를 써줘.
고마워.
Alright, let me see how I'm going to start.
좋아, 이렇게 시작하면 어떨까.
Dear baby adoption decider people
애기 입양을 결정하는 사람들에게..
So excited about your letter.
네 추천서가 정말 기대되는구나.
Hey
안녕?
Hi Phoebe.
안녕, 피비?
와~ 왠일로 예쁘게 차려입었네.
Wow, don't you look nice.
그래, 좀 예쁘게 입었지.
Yes, I do.
Today's, uh, Mike and my one year anniversary.
오늘이 바로 마이크랑 나랑 1년 되는 날이야.
Oh, what's it the anniversary of?
오, 무슨 1년 되는 날인데?
Your first, uh, date? Your first kiss?
처음으로 데이트 한지 1년?
아니면 첫 키스한지?
First time you had sex?
아니면 처음으로 잔 지 1년?
응, 그거야.
Yeah!
So you must be going somewhere fancy to celebrate.
그럼 1년 기념하려 멋진 데로 가겠네?
Uh-huh. Um, uh, Knicks game.
응, 어.. 닉스 게임 보러 가.
Uh...aren't you a little over-dressed?
그런 거라면 좀 너무 차려 입은 거 아니야?
Hey, you know what?
I've never had a one year anniversary before
그렇게 보여? 그래도 난 말야,
1년 기념 같은거 처음으로 해보는 거란 말이야
so no matter where we go, I'm wearig something fancy pants
그러니까 어딜 가든 난 좋은 옷을 입고,
and I'm going to put on my finest jewelry and
제일 좋은 악세서리를 하고
we're going to have sex in a public restroom
또, 공중 화장실에서 섹스도 할거야.
You guys do that?
와, 너네 공중 화장실에서도 한단 말야?
Chandler won't even have sex in our bathroom.
챈들러는 우리 집 화장실에서도 싫다던데.
That's where people make number 2.
사람들이 X 싸는 데서 어떻게 그걸 해!
Friends 10x05 TOW Rachel's sister baby-sits
영어대본 by K. Kim
FㆍRㆍIㆍEㆍNㆍDㆍS
10x05. The One Where
Rachel's Sister Baby-Sits
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON NBC: 2003/10/30
자막제작 - 코리아닷컴 프렌즈 동호회
(http://club.korea.com/friends)
[ 번 역 ]
김효진(with0124@korea.com)
[ 싱 크 ]
김은진 (yeooo4@korea.com)
임욱재(sys_friends6@korea.com)
[ 테스트 ]
신우철(berlitz@korea.com)
[ 게스트 ]
이승훈(chandler7@korea.com)
자막에 관련된 문의는 동호회에 있는
'자막 피드백게시판'으로 해주세요~
Hey / Hi
- 안녕?
- 안녕
So you know, I have a little time
if you, uh, you want to ....
참고로 난 시간이 좀 있는데..
혹시 너도..?
Oh
아…나도 그러고 싶지만
난 지금 학생들 성적 채점 해야돼.
Oh, I'd love to but I really have to grade these papers
Ah, fine. It's fine.
그래, 어쩔 수 없지.
혼자서 샤워하면 되지 뭐.
I'll just shower by myself.
B, B, B, B, B.
B..
B,B..
B,B,B..
B,B,B,B..
B,B,B,B,B..
Oh, Ross you gave a B to a pottery barn catalog.
로스, 포터리 반(주) 카탈로그에까지
B를 주면 어떡해.
Well, it had some good ideas. Take off your shirt.
꽤 괜찮은 카탈로그여서 준거야.
셔츠 벗자.
젠장!
Damn it.
Rachel! Open up! It's your sister.
언니 문열어!! 나야!! 할 말 있어!!
I have to talk to you.
Hi, Amy.
안녕, 에이미?
You're not Rachel.
레이첼이 아니네요.
Still sharp as a tack!
여전히 하나도 안 변했네요!!
Um, Charlie, this is Rachel's sister, Amy.
찰리, 이쪽은 레이첼 동생 에이미고,
에이미, 이쪽은 찰리야.
Amy, this is Charlie.
Hi, nice to meet you/ Hi
- 반가워요.
- 반갑네요.
그런데 당신은..?
And you are?
Ross.
로스에요.
I grew up on your block?
당신네 동네에서 살았던 그..
Um
음…
We had thanksgiving together last year?
작년에 추수 감사절에 식사도 같이 했잖아요?
I had a baby with your sister?
당신 언니 아이의 아빠이기도 한 로스라구요!
Did I buy a falafel from you yesterday?
아, 혹시 어제 길거리에서
팔라펠(주) 팔던 아저씨 아니에요?
네, 네, 맞아요.
Yes, yes you did.
Hi, Rachel. Here's your sister, Amy.
레이첼, 네 동생 에이미 왔어.
She thinks I need peck implants
나더러 모발이식이 필요하대
Amy, hi.
에이미, 오랜만이야. 조이 기억해?
You remember Joey?
Yeah, sure. The days of our lives guy.
물론이야. '우리들의 나날' 에 나왔잖아.
That's right.
맞아요.
You were not good.
당신 정말 별로였죠.
팬을 만나는 건 언제나 기쁘군요.
Always nice to meet a fan.
그래, 여긴 왠일이야?
So now what are you doing here?
Well, I have huge news
사실 정말 엄청난 소식이 있어.
Sorry. Hold on. Let me just check on the baby
잠깐만 기다려 줄래? 애기 좀 보고 올게.
Wait! This is important. Can't Ella wait?
언니 잠깐만! 정말 중요한 얘기란 말야.
엘라는 조금 있다 보면 안돼?
Uh, her name is Emma.
저, 엘라가 아니라 에마인데요.
어머, 왜 바꿨어요?
엘라가 훨씬 더 예쁜데.
Why did you change it?
Ella was so much prettier.
What do I know?
I just sell middle eastern food from a cart.
저도 잘 모르겠네요.
전 손수레 끌면서 팔라펠이나 파는 남잔걸요.
Hey, your English is getting better.
와, 영어 실력이 점점 좋아지고 있어요!
Oh my God. / I know
오, 이럴수가..
그러게. 아마 내가 싫어한 여자 중에
제일 섹시한 여자가 아닐까 싶어.
She may be the hottest girl I've ever hated.
어, 지금 뭐 쓰고 있는거야?
What you...what you're working on?
Oh, Monica and Chandler's recommendation.
모니카랑 챈들러 추천서.
난 똑똑하게 보이도록 쓰고 싶은데,
난 어려운 말 같은 거 잘 모르잖아..
I want it to sound smart
but I don't know any big words or any of those so...
Why don't you use your thesaurus?
그럼 용어 대체 사전을 써보면 어때?
What did I just say?
방금 어려운 말 모른다고 한거 못들었어?
이걸 봐.
Watch
Here you, uh, you hightlight the word you want to change
니가 바꾸고 싶은 말을 지정한 다음에
go into tools and the thesaurus generates....gives,
'도구' 로 가면 용어 대체 사전이
제공..이 아니라, 보여줄꺼야.
gives a whole list of choices.
니가 바꿀 수 있는 단어들 목록이 나와.
제일 똑똑해 보이는 말로 고르면 되는 거지!
You can pick the word that sounds smartest,
Oh my God, that's great!
우와! 이거 좋다!
나는 똑똑하다! 가 아니라 나는..
I'm smart.
No, no, I am
brainy, bright, clever! I love this thing!
머리 좋다, 총명하다, 영리하다!!
이거 너무 좋은 거 아냐?!!
Look out, ladies! Joey Tribbiani's got the whole package!
이것 좀 봐요 아가씨들~~
조이 트리비아니가 준비를 다 마쳤습니다!
와..너무 예쁘다 정말..
So beautiful
Oh, I know. Isn't she?
정말 예쁘지 애기?
No, I was talking about your bedding.
아니, 난 침대 커버 말한거야.
Alright. What's your news, Amy?
좋아, 네 소식이란 건 뭐니?
Oh.
사실..나 결혼해!
Well,
I'm getting married.
Wow! Oh my God!
어머나, 누구랑?
To who?
어떤 남자랑!
This guy...
He has a killer apartment
그사람 아파트가 진짜 끝내줘!!
그리고..?
and....?
And it's on 5th and the elevator opens up
right into the living room.
그리고 5번가에 있고,
엘리베이터가 열리자마자 거실로 통해!!
No, what's...what's he like?
그래, 근데 내 말은 그 사람은 어떤 사람이나고?
Oh, he's okay.
괜찮은 사람이야.
Do you remember my old boyfriend, Mark? / Yeah.
- 내가 전에 사귀었던 마크라는 애 기억나?
- 응
It's his Dad.
그 마크의 아빠야.
Ha! Well, so he's got to be...
- 그럼 그사람 정말…
- 늙었겠다고? 응, 맞아.
Old? Yeah.
But he travels a lot so he's hardly ever there.
그런데 여행하느라 잘 들어오진 않아.
에이미, 내가 듣기엔 그 사람 아파트를
좀 더 좋아하는 것처럼 들려.
Pretty, I 've got to tell you it sounds a little bit
like you like the apartment more than you like ...
그사람을 좋아한다기 보다..
그사람 이름이..?
Myron.
마이런.
Um, yeah, I told you he was old.
말했잖아 나이 많다고.
Ugh, sit down. Sit down.
잠깐 앉아봐, 앉아봐.
Oh honey, you know. I once also almost married somebody
that I didn't love.
나 역시 내가 원하지 않는 사람하고
거의 결혼할 뻔 했었어. 배리 기억나?
Do you remember Barry?
그럼 기억나지.
언니 잠든 다음에 둘이 키스하곤 했는데..
Remember him?
God, we used to make out all the time after you went to sleep.
Sometimes just nodding is okay.
가끔 자세히 얘기 안하고
고개만 끄덕여도 괜찮을텐데 말야?
Um , so but anyway, listen. Not marrying Barry was
the best decision that I ever, ever made.
근데 어찌됐든.. 배리랑 결혼하지
않은 건 내 생애에 했던 결정중에
가장 옳았던 결정이었어.
Honey, Amy, you, you deserve true love
에이미, 넌 진정한 사랑을 할 자격이 있고,
네 운명의 상대는 분명히 어딘가에 있을 거야.
Your, your soul mate is out there somewhere
Someone that is your age that is smart that is fun
네 나이 또래에, 똑똑하고 재밌는..
그리고 네가 좋아할 만한 그런 사람이..
and that, that you care about.
You're right. You're right
맞아, 맞아.
I'm going to do it /Okay
결심했어.
I'm going to marry Myron and keep looking for Mr. Right.
마이런이랑 결혼하고 나서
운명의 상대를 찾아 나서겠어.
Okay
잠깐, 조금만 더 얘기해야겠다.
Okay. Let's keep talking
Excuse me. Anniversary.
잠깐만요, 1년 기념일이에요.
잠깐만요, 1년 기념일이거든요.
Excuse me. Anniversary.
Um, yeah.
저기요, 나쵸 좀 치워주시겠어요?
제 자린데요.
Sir, could you, could you move your Nachos.
They're on my seat.
It's my anniversary.
저희 1년 기념일이라서요.
Here we are.
드디어 여기까지 왔네요.
우리가 1년이나 됐다니 믿기지가 않아요.
Can't believe it's been a whole year.
I know.
그래요. 정말 내 인생에서..
This has been the best year ....
This has been the best year of my life / Me too.
내 인생에서 가장 행복한 1년이었어요.
저두요.
I've never thought I'd love someone this much
이렇게까지 누군가를
사랑하게 될 줄은 몰랐어요
나도 그래요.
I feel the same way
당신은 정말 착하고 친절하고
잠자리도 끝내줘요!!
You're so generous and kind
and you're amazing in bed!
It's our anniversary.
1년 기념일이거든요 저희.
Knicks fans. Please turn your attention
to the big screen on the scoreboards.
닉스 팬 여러분,
점수판 스크린에 주목해 주세요.
Someone has a special question to ask.
누군가 특별히 할말이 있다는군요.
아, 시시해!
Oh, how lame!
Oh, it's so tacky and impersonal.
너무 촌스러운 데다가 비인격적이에요.
- 정말요?
- 정말 최악의 프로포즈 법이라구요.
Really?
Oh, it's the worst way to propose.
Excuse me.
잠깐만 좀 다녀올게요.
자, 여기 내 추천서야.
Hey. Here's my recommendation, here.
And I think you would be very, very happy.
상당히 만족할 거라고 믿어.
포르노 안 보고 이렇게 컴퓨터 앞에
오래 앉아 있다니 신기록이야.
It's the longest I've ever spent on a computer
without looking at porn.
I don't, uh, understand.
저 난, 무슨 말인지 모르겠어.
Some of the words are a little too sophisticated for you.
네가 이해하기엔
너무 세련된 단어들을 쓰긴 했지.
It doesn't make any sense.
그게 아니라 아예 말이 안되는데.
말이 안되긴 왜 안돼! 똑똑한 단어들이란 말이야! 용어 대체 사전도 썼다구.
Of course it does. It's smart.
I used the thesaurus
On every word?
모든 단어에 다?
Yup
응.
Alright. What was this sentence originally?
원래 이 문장은 무슨 문장이었던 거야?
Oh. "They're warm, nice people with big hearts."
그들은 넓은 심장(가슴)을
가진 따뜻하고 착한 사람들입니다.
And that became "They're humid, preposessing
homo-sapience with full-sized aortic pumps."
그런데 그게..'그들은 대형의 대동맥 염통을 가진 눅눅하고 호감을 주는 현세인입니다' 가 된거야?
응, 그리고 그건 내 진심이야.
Yeah, yeah.
And hey, I really mean it, dude.
Hey, Joey. I don't think we can use this.
조이, 이걸 추천서로 내진 못할 것 같아.
Why not?
왜 안돼?!
Well, because you signed it, "Baby Kangaroo Tribbiani"
왜냐면 네가 '아기 캥거루 트리비아니'라고
싸인했으니까.
Honey, why don't you stop worrying about sounding smart
and just be yourself?
조이, 똑똑하게 보이려고 애쓰지 말고
그냥 자연스럽게 하는게 어때?
You know what? You don't need the thesaurus.
Just right from here.
그래, 용어 대체 사전 같은 건 필요 없어.
그냥 바로 여기서 느끼는 대로 쓰면 돼.
Your full-sized aortic pump.
너의 '대형 대동맥 염통'에서 느끼는대로!
Amy, hi.
에이미, 왠일이야?
I took your advice. I left Myron.
언니가 말한대로 하기로 했어.
마이런하고 헤어졌어.
Oh, good for you! / I know!
- 정말 잘됐다!
- 응 그렇지?
난 에린 브로코비치(주)야!!
I'm Erin Brockovich!
Yes, you are!
응, 그래. 네가 정말 자랑스럽다.
Oh, I'm so pround of you / Oh, thank you.
고마워, 언니.
그래서 말인데, 언니네 집에서 지내도 되지?
So can I stay with you?
But Erin Brockovich had her own house.
하지만.. 에린 브로코비치는
자기 집에서 살았는데..?
Ah...look who's back.
어이, 또 왔네.
아니 왜 짐을 가져온거야? 레이첼,
왜 얘 짐이 여기 있는거야??
Why do you have bags?
Rachel, why does she have bags?
I'm staying with you guys.
이 집에서 지내려구요.
What?
뭐라구요?
We're going to be roomies. Come on.
우린 룸메이트가 되는거에요!
짐 들여놔요.
밖에서 잔거야?
Slept out here?
응, 에이미가 자꾸 "마이런 저리가!" 라고
잠꼬대 하면서 발로 차잖아.
Well, Amy kept kicking me in her sleep
yelling "Myron, get off"
But, uh, we're getting rid of her, right?
그래도.. 나가라고 할 꺼지, 그치?
Rach, please tell me we're getting rid of her.
제발 그렇다고 해줘. 나가라고 할 꺼지?
Joey, I can't do that!
조이, 그럴 수는 없어.
Oh, come on!
제발 부탁이야. 어젯밤엔 어땠는 줄 알아?
내가 남은 피자를 마저 먹고 있는데 이러는거야.
Last night I was finishing off a pizza and she said
" Whoa, whoa, whoa.
The moment on the lips, forever on the hips"
"조심해요! 한 순간 입의 즐거움이
영원히 엉덩이 살로 남는 수가 있다구요."
I don't need that kind of talk in my house.
우리 집에서 그런 말 듣고 싶지 않단 말야!!!
조이, 나도 걔가 상대하기 힘든 애란 걸 알아.
하지만 에이미가 여기 있는게 좋을 것 같아.
Joey. Look, I know that she's difficult.
But I think it's really good that she's here.
Cause we'll appreciate it more when she's gone?
여깄는게 좋다구?
없어졌을 때 더 행복하기 위해서?
아니, 뭐냐면.. 알잖아. 처음 뉴욕에 왔을 때
나는 꼭 지금의 에이미 같았어.
No, it's just ...Look, you know, when I first moved to the city,
I was a lot like her.
I was spoiled, self-centered
and you guys really took care of me.
제멋대로에, 자기 중심적인데다..
그런데 너희들이 날 잘 돌봐준거잖아.
Yeah, Monica made us.
그렇지, 모니카가 억지로 그러라고 시켰으니까.
어쨌든, 난 그게 너무 고마워.
왜냐면 너희들이 아니었다면
Well, whatever.
I really appreciate it cause
I don't think I would be the person that I am today
if it wasn't for you guys
난 지금의 내 모습이 되어있지
못할 거란 걸 알기 때문이야.
So you know, I want to help Amy for you guys helped me
너희들이 나를 도와줬듯이
나도 에이미를 도와주고 싶고,
And I know it's going to take patience but that's okay
물론 인내심이 필요할 거란 걸 알지만
난 괜찮아.
- 굿모닝!
- 그래~
Good morning / Yeah
Amy, that's what I was supposed to wear today.
에이미, 그거 내가 오늘 입으려고했던 옷이야.
그래서 문에다가 일부러 걸어 놨잖아.
That's why I hung it on the door.
어머 언니, 언니는 이 옷 소화 못해.
Oh, sweetie. You can't pull this off.
Amy, you know what?
에이미, 생각해 봤는데,
이제는 우리가 마주 앉아
I was thinking that, um, maybe now would be a good time
for us to sit down
and ,uh, you know talk about your future.
네 미래에 대해 얘기를 좀 해봤으면 좋겠어.
Oh, I can't, honey. I'm going to go get my eyebrow shaped
아 그건 안되겠어 언니.
지금 눈썹 하러 갈꺼거든.
매우 마음에 안들어.
I am not happy
어, 정말 그거 먹을 거에요?
Oh, sure you want to eat that?
I'm curvy and I like it!
난 통통한 내모습이 좋단말이에요!
Hi / Hi
I just had the worst anniversary ever.
정말 최악의 1년 기념일이었어.
아마 아닐걸. 우리 작년에 어땠는지 얘기해줘.
I doubt that. Tell her about ours last year.
Oh, well, I bought Chandler a 500 dollar watch
나는 챈들러한테 500달러짜리 시계를 줬고
챈들러는 나한테 랩을 지어줬어.
and he wrote me a rap song.
Seriously?
정말이야?
Word
맞아
(word : 레퍼들이 자주사용하는
'맞다'라는 의미의 슬랭)
Well, mine was worse than that
우리 쪽이 더 최악이었어.
Well, what happened?
무슨 일이 있었길래?
We were at the game and this guy proposed to his girlfriend
on the big screen thing
경기를 보고 있었는데 어떤 남자가
경기장 대형 스크린에서
여자친구한테 프로포즈를 하는거야.
아 그거, 그거 너무 촌스러워.
Oh, that is so tacky.
Well, that's what I said.
그래, 나도 그렇게 말했어.
But it turns out Mike was planning on proposing to me
that same way last night.
그런데 알고 보니까 마이크도
어젯밤에 똑같은 방법으로
나한테 프로포즈하려고 했던거야.
Oh my God! Mike was going to propose?
웬일이니! 마이크가 프로포즈하려고 했다고?
Phoebe, that's huge
- 엄청나다..
- 너는 마이크랑 결혼할 생각이 있는거야?
Well, do you want to marry him?
응, 나도 정말 하고 싶어!!
Ah, yeah! I really do!
Yes but after I dumped on the way
he was going to propose to me
근데 마이크가 프로포즈하려는 방법이
촌스럽다고 말해서 실망시켜버렸으니
이제 다시는 나한테 프로포즈 안할 꺼 같아.
I don't think he's ever going to ask again.
I mean I said no on Barbados and now this?
바베이도스에서도 결혼 안한다고 했는데
이번에도 이렇게 되고..
She's right. If I were a guy and...
그래 맞아. 만약 내가 남자라면..
Did I just say "If I were a guy"?
내가 방금 '만약 내가 남자라면' 이라고 한거야?
Maybe you don't need him to propose to you.
어쩌면 마이크가 프로포즈하길 기다릴 게 아니라
네가 마이크한테 프로포즈할 수도 있잖아.
Maybe you can propose to him.
Oh, I don't know.
그건 잘 모르겠다. 사실..
너무 매달리는 것처럼 보이잖아?
I don't know. Isn't that a little desperate?
I proposed to Chandler.
나 챈들러한테 프로포즈 했었잖아.
좋아, 넘어가자.
Alright. Moving on.
-Well, I don't think it was desperate. I think it was amazing.
-Thank you
난 매달린다고 생각하지 않았어.
멋지다고 생각했어.
고마워.
네가 보기에도 내가 프로포즈해야 될 것 같아?
Well, do you think I should propose?
I think it could be kind of great.
내 생각엔 굉장히 멋질 수도 있을 거 같아.
물론이지! 너도 그 느낌을 좋아하게 될거야.
프로포즈만큼 재밌는게 또 없지!!
Absolutely! You'll love the feeling. There's nothing like it!
Okay. okay.
그래, 그래. 그러면, 어떤 방법으로 하지?
So how should I do it?
How about at a game on the big screen?
경기장 대형 스크린을 이용하는 건 어때?
Huh! How about at a foot locker?
그래? 차라리 신발가게에서 하겠다!
What?
뭐가? 확실히 마이크는 그렇게 하는게
괜찮은 방법이라고 생각하고 있는 거잖아.
What? He obviously thinks that's a nice way to be proposed to.
Plus, he'd never suspect it.
게다가, 이럴 거라곤 예상도 못할거란 말이야.
Yeah, that does make sense.
그래, 말된다.
Okay. Now would, would you two like that?
너희 둘은 어떻게 생각해?
Sounds good to me.
내 생각엔 좋은 거 같은데.
하지만 남자애들은 어떻게 생각할까?
But what would a guy think?
Uh, nana's on the phone.
언니, 나나 전화야.
Well, it's interesting since she died seven years ago
희한한 일이네. 7년 전에 돌아가신 분이.
She did?
정말이야?
그럼 보카(주)에 있는 콘도는 누가 받았어?
Who got her condo on Boca?
Hello
여보세요?
It's our nanny
나나가 아니라 우리 내니(보모)잖아.
Hi
어머 그래요? 빨리 나아요.
알았어요, 다음에 봐요.
Oh God. I hope you feel better.
Okay. Bye.
That's Molly. She's sick
몰리야. 아프대.
Can you watch Emma today?
오늘 에마 좀 봐줄 수 있어?
아니, 나 오늘 계속 연속으로 수업이 있어.
몰리 무슨 병이래? 요즘 계속 목이 아파서..
I can't. I have back to back classes.
Did Molly say what she had?
Because my throat's been hurting
생리통이래.
Menstral cramps
I don't think that's what this is
나는 그건 아닌 것 같아.
Can any of you watch Emma?
혹시 에마 봐줄 수 있는 사람 없어?
No, sorry sweetie
미안, 레이첼.
No. I've got work and then I'm proposing.
난 일도 해야되고 프로포즈도 해야 되고.
이런, 어떡하지?
Shoot. What are we going to do?
Oh, I can do it
음, 내가 할께.
Well, actually.
그래, 사실 네가..
Can I talk to you for a sec? / Yeah.
나랑 잠깐 얘기 좀 할까?
Um, I do not want her baby-sitting our child
나는 쟤가 우리 아이를 보는걸 원치 않아.
Why not?
왜 싫은데?
Well, for one thing, she keeps calling her Ella.
우선 첫째로 자꾸만 우리 아이를 '엘라' 라고 불러.
엘라도 예쁜 이름이잖아.
Ella's a nice name.
Fine. We'll call the next one Ella.
좋아, 그럼 둘째를 엘라라고 짓든지.
What? The next one? / Okay.
뭐? 둘째라고?
그게 아니라.. 난 에이미가 우리 애기를
보지 않았으면 좋겠어.
I don't want her watching our baby.
로스, 난 지금 에이미가
좋은 사람이 되도록 도우려고 하고 있어.
Ross, I am trying to help her become a better person.
This is a huge breakthrough for her
지금 에이미는 큰 발전을 한거야.
다른 사람을 위해서 무언가 하겠다고 나섰잖아.
She just offered to do something for another human being
Honey, I, I don't know
레이첼, 그래도 난 잘..
Ross, I'm telling you. She's giving up
getting her eyebrows shaped to do this, alright?
로스, 들어줘. 지금 에이미는 아기를 보겠다고
자기 눈썹 정리를 포기한거야, 응?
그게 우리 세계에서
얼마나 중요한 일인지 알아?
Do you understand how important that is in our world?
Ah...Listen. I couldn't help but overhear
저… 듣지 않을 수가 없었어요.
cause I was trying to
들으려고 귀기울였으니까.
Listen, let me do this.
시켜주세요. 나 정말 두 사람 돕고 싶어요.
언니가 나한테 너무 잘해주기도 했고..
I really want to help you guys out and, and
plus Rachel's been so wonderful to me.
잘 부탁해, 에이미.
Absolutely
Oh, great
아, 잘됐다. 그런데 시간 당 얼마인가요?
So how much does it pay?
조이, 추천서 두번째 초고는 잘 돼가?
Hey, Joe. How's the second draft of the letter coming?
Great. I'm finished
잘 돼, 다 끝났어. 사실 방금
입양 에이젼시에다 내고 오는 길이야.
In fact, I just dropped it off at the agency
You dropped it off? / Yeah
- 내버렸다고?
- 응.
우리가 읽어볼 순 없는거야?
하나 더 프린트해주면 안돼?
Can we read it? Can you print out another copy?
No can't do, amigo.
미안하지만 안되겠어 친구.
No, I didn't use a computer.
I felt more personal to hand-write it.
아니, 컴퓨터로 친게 아니라서.
손으로 쓰는게 더 정감이 느껴지잖아.
You hand-wrote it?
손으로 썼다고?
응, 그리고 걱정할 필요 전혀 없어.
전혀 똑똑하게 보이려고
노력하지 않았으니까. 전혀!
Yeah and don't worry. I didn't try to sound smart at all!
See you later
나중에 봐.
이럴수가, 이런 일이.. 그 추천서가
우리 파일에 들어가 버릴거야.
Oh my God! Oh my God!
That letter's going to go in our file.
We're never going to get a kid
평생 아이 키울 일은 없게 될거란 말야.
No, we're going to, we're going to be one of those old couples
that collects orchids or
우린 난초나 새를 엄청 많이 기르는
늙은 커플이 될거야.
has a lot of birds.
아니야, 아니야. 괜찮을거야.
It's okay. It's okay. You know what?
I will just call the agency and tell them
to throw out the letter / Okay. Good
- 지금 전화해서 그 편지를 버리라고 말할께.
- 그래 그러자
Hello, this is Chandler Bing.
Somebody just dropped off a hand-written recommendation letter and
안녕하세요, 챈들러 빙인데요.
아마 지금 누군가 손으로 쓴 추천서를
접수시켰을 텐데요, 그게..
네. 아, 네. 그렇군요. 감사합니다.
Ah ha.
Ah ha
Okay
Thank you. Good bye
Oh, we're screwed, aren't we.
이제 끝나버린 거지? 이럴 게 아니라
새 가게에 가면서 얘기하자.
You know what? Just tell me on the way to the bird store
They loved it / What?
- 추천서 좋았대.
- 뭐라구?
어린애한테 추천서를 쓰게 하다니
괜찮은 생각이었다고 하던데.
They thought it was very smart of us to have a child
write the recommendation letter
조이가 어린애인 줄 안거야?
They thought Joey was a child?
She guessed 8, 9 based on his drawings.
그림 그린 걸로 봐서는
여덟, 아홉 살 정도라고 생각했대.
Hi.
있었네요?
Hey, what did you guys do today?
오늘 뭐하고 놀았어요?
Ella wanted to go out.
엘라가 밖에 나가고 싶다더라구요.
So we went shopping and got some sushi
그래서 쇼핑하러 갔다가 초밥도 먹고 그랬죠.
That sounds like fun / Yeah, not really
- 재밌었겠네요.
- 아뇨, 그다지요.
애기들은 재미없어요.
Babies are dull
왔어? 어머나, 우리 애기 잘 지냈어?
Hey
Hi, how's my girl?
Oh, I'm fine
그럼, 나야 잘 지냈지.
And I got you a present for letting me stay with you
그리고 같이 지내게 해준 게 고마워서
선물을 하나 준비했어.
Ready? / Yup
- 준비됐지?
- 응!
Ta-da
짜잔~
You piereced her ears?
우리 애기 귀를 뚫은 거야?!
이러니까 코가 더 작아보이지 않아?!
Doesn't it make her nose look smaller?
우리 애기 귀를 뚫었단 말이야??
You pierced her ears?
How could you do this without telling me?
나한테 말도 없이 어떻게 그럴 수가 있어?!
Well, if I had told you,
then it wouldn't have been a surprise. Now would it?
미리 말을 했다면 깜짝 선물이 아니잖아, 안그래?
I think she looks cute
내가 보기엔 귀여운 것 같은데.
하지만 내 생각은 틀렸어.
but I am wrong
Oh my God. Oh my God. Here comes Ross.
오, 이럴수가, 이럴수가.. 로스가 오네.
He is going to flip out
이거 보면 무지 열받을 텐데.
Why? Did something happen to his falafel cart?
왜? 팔라펠 가게에 뭐 문제라도 있나?
Hi Guys / Hey Ross
- 안녕 얘들아?
- 안녕 로스?
Ross / Hi Emma
안녕 에마? 왜이렇게 모자를
푹 눌러쓰고 있는거야? 잘 못보잖아.
Oh, why is she wearing her hat so low?
-She can barely see
-I don't really want her to see
오, 난 안보는 게 더 좋을 거 같은데.
Why, why not?
왜 안보는게 나은데?
왜냐면, 세상엔 너무나
안좋은 광경들이 많잖아.
Because there are so many terrible sights in this world
예를 들면 전쟁이라든지,
또, 조이 냉장고에 들어있던 그거 기억나?
Like war
or that that thing in Joey's refrigerator. Remember?
It was in a milk carton but it, it looked like meat.
우유팩 속에 있던 건데 고기처럼 생긴 그거?
자, 보자, 안녕?
Come here, come here. HA!
여깄네 우리 에마. 안녕?
There she is. Hi
What?
왜?
Nothing
아무 것도 아니야.
안녕?
Hi
엉?..
What?
허억!!
Please tell me those are clip-ons.
똑딱이라고 말해줘!
아니야, 진짜 뚫은거야.
Oh, they're real
Did she do this to her?
설마 쟤가 이런 짓을 한거야?
내가 말했잖아!! 쟤한테 에마 맡기면 안된다고!
I told you we shouldn't have left Emma with her
I know. I know and you were right, Ross. Okay?
알아, 알아. 그리고 네 말이 맞았어 로스. 응?
You are so irresponsible.
I am never letting you baby-sit ever again
너 정말 무책임해.
절대 너한테 다시는 애기 맡기지 않을거야.
Hey, you know what? This kid needs me, okay?
언니, 그거 알아? 이 애는 내가 필요해, 알았어?
얘한테도 멋지고 재밌는 이모가 필요하다구!
She needs to have a cool fun aunt.
I'm a cool fun aunt / Okay
- 나도 멋지고 재밌는 이모인데요?
- 물론 그렇겠죠.
Hey, Monica can be cool and fun
and organize indoor projects.
이봐요. 모니카도 실내 정리 프로젝트에서는
멋지고 재밌을 수 있다구요.
I can't believe this. All I wanted to do is help you
try to figure out what to do with your life
이럴 수가. 정말 믿기지가 않아.
난 네가 앞으로 무얼 할지를 생각해 볼 수 있도록
도와주려고 했던 것뿐이야.
그런데 넌 나한테 이런 식으로 갚는거야?
And this is how you repay me?
Well, I don't need you to help me
사실 난 이제 언니 도움 필요 없어.
이미 내가 뭘 할지를 알게 됐거든.
because I already know what I'm going to do with my life
아 정말이니? 언제부터?
Oh, yeah? Since when?
오늘부터
Since today
I am going to be...
난 애기 스타일리스트가 될꺼야!
a baby-stylist
- 뭐?
- 그런 게 어딨어!
What?
That's not a thing!
Well, it should be.
왜요, 난 애기들한테 가르쳐 주고 싶어요.
어떤 액세서리를 해야 되는지,
I'm going to help babies learn how to accesorize,
what colors to wear,
어떤 색을 입어야 하는지,
어떤 옷이 날씬해 보이는지.
what clothes are slimmin'
Babies don't care if they're slim!
애기들은 날씬하든 말든 신경 안써!
Enter Amy
에이미에게로 오라!
에이미, 난 정말, 이제부터, 정말로..!
Amy, I just, I just, I just want to....
뭔데요? 어떻게 하실려구요?
What? What are you going to do?
No more falafel for you!
너한테는 팔라펠 안팔꺼야!!!!
Great game, huh?
- 경기 좋죠?
- 네, 네.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh
왜 자꾸 스크린을 보는거에요?
Why do you keep looking at the screen?
I'm not. I'm praying
아니에요, 그냥 기도하는거에요.
오, 제발 닉스가 이기게 해주세요.
Please let the Knicks win
감사합니다. 토르(주)여.
Thank you, Thor
- 어디 가는거에요?
- 화장실이요.
Where're you, where're you going?
I'm going to go to the bathroom.
Well, I think you should wait / Why?
- 좀 기다렸다 가는 게 좋겠네요.
- 왜요?
Well, if you don't, if you don't hold it in,
그러지 않으면, 좀 더 참지 않으면..
영양분이 빠져나가 버리잖아요.
you don't, you don't get all the nutrients
Knicks fans. Please turn your attention
to the big screen on the scoreboard
닉스 팬 여러분. 점수판의 대형 스크린에
주목해 주시기 바랍니다.
누군가 특별한 부탁이 있다는군요.
Someone has a special question to ask
Mike Hanigan, will you marry me?
마이크 해니건, 나와 결혼해 주겠어요?
Get a load of this
이것 좀 보세요.
여자분이 남자분한테 프로포즈를 하는 거군요!
She's proposing to him
Guess we know who wears the pants in that family
앞으로 저 집안에서
누가 주도권을 잡을지 두고 봅시다!
That's not very enlightened
그 말은 너무 전근대적이군요.
Hey, hey
이것봐요, 이것봐!
우리한테 야유하는거야?
당신들한테나 야유해!
Boo us? Boo you!
Hello
여보세요. 네, 제가 조이 트리비아니인데요.
Yeah, this is Joey Tribbiani
Oh, hi.
네, 안녕하세요!
I'm glad you liked my letter
아, 제 편지가 맘에 드셨다니 다행이네요.
No, my mommy and daddy aren't home right now
아뇨, 우리 엄마 아빠 지금 집에 안계신데요.
Okay. Bye bye.
알았어요, 안녕.
She was nice
친절하네~
조이, 에이미 짐 좀 싸줘! 내보낼꺼야!
Joey, get Amy's bags. She is moving out!
아싸~!
Oohoo!
언니 지금 날 쫓아내는 거야?
You're kicking me out?!
넌 내 아기의 귀에 구멍을 뚫었어!
You put holes in my baby's ears.
그래, 그래도 최소한 그 덕분에 사람들이
이제야 걔가 여자애인걸 알 수 있게 됐잖아!
Yeah, well, at least now people will know she's a girl!
I can't believe I have even tried to help you!
내가 너를 도와주겠다고 생각한 것부터가
잘못이지!! 넌 정말 구제불능이야!
You are so beyond help
You know what?
언니, 그거 알아? 내가 여기 온 뒤부터
언니는 계속 나한테 부정적이기만 했어.
Ever since I've got here, you have been nothing but negative
뭐라구?
Excuse me?
멋있는 아파트가 있는 노인하고
결혼하는 것도 반대했지?
You didn't want me to marry
the old guy with the great apartment
그리고 내가 언니 딸 얼굴의 결점들에서
시선을 분산시키려고 노력했는데 말야.
Then I tried to help your daughter de-emphasize her flaws
And suddenly I'm the bad guy?
이제와서 나만 나쁜 사람인거야?
조이, 짐 빨리 좀 가져와!!!
Joey, where are those bags?!
She has a lot of crap!
엉망 진창으로 늘어져 있단 말이야!
You know what?
내가 여기서 지내기로 했을 때 나는 이제부터
정말 재밌어질거라고 생각했어.
When I moved in here, I thought this is going to be so great.
Just us sisters back together again like when we were kids
우리 자매들이 어렸을 때처럼 다시 모여서
지내구 말야. 그 멍청한 질은 빼고.
except without that stupid Jill.
Oh, who has gotten fat by the way?
오, 참고로 질 엄청 살쪘다!!
Seriously? / Um-hmm
- 진짜?
- 응.
Mom says she gained like 15 pounds
엄마가 그러는데 한 8킬로는 쪘나봐!
엉덩이야 허벅지야?
Hips or thighs?
Ass and face / Oh!
- 엉덩이랑 얼굴!
- 어머나 왠일이니
Oh my God!
I thought she was on Atkins
황제 다이어트(주)하는줄 알았는데!
She was. Carbs found her
그랬지. 근데 탄수화물을 못참았나봐
See?
이것봐.. 난 이런 걸 바랬던 거야.
두 자매가 모여서 진지한 얘기도 하고.
This is what I wanted.
Two sisters talking about real stuff
Oh, I can't give you that
그래 나도 그럴 수 있어.
응 할 수 있어.
You can / Yeah
I just, I keep trying to make you a better person
난 지금 너를 괜찮은
사람으로 만들려고 노력하고 있었는데,
but you're, you're already
a pretty perfect version of what you are
넌 이미 너의 세계에서 완벽한 사람이 됐어.
Thank you
고마워
I've got to admit Emma does look cute
난..에마가 귀엽다는 걸 인정할께.
Did you just say Emma?
방금 너.. 에마라고 부른거야?
Oh, I'm sorry. Ella.
휴..미안. 엘라였지.
That woman at the game didn't know
what she was talking about
경기장에서의 그 여자는
아무 생각 없이 그런 말을 한거에요.
마이크, 물론 당신에게도 용기가 있죠!
(balls : 속어로 남자의 고환)
Mike, obviously you have balls
그냥 우리 모든 걸 다 잊어버리는 게 어때요?
Please let's just forget the whole thing.
I would love it
- 그래요, 그게 좋겠네요.
잊혀진 일이라고 쳐요.
- 고마워요
Consider it forgotten / Thank you
But just so you know
말해두는 건데요. 어떤 방법이든 언제든
당신이 프로포즈 하려고 결심하면
나는 분명히 허락할거라 약속해요.
however and whenever you decide to propose,
I promise I'll say yes
Whether, whether, you know,
it's at a basketball game or in skywriting
농구 경기장이든,
비행기로 하늘에 글자를 쓰든,
or you know like some lame guy in a cheesy movie,
" Hide it in the cake"
아니면 구닥다리 영화에서
촌뜨기 남자가 하듯
"케잌 안에 숨겼어요!" 라고 하더라도..
It's in the cake, isn't it?
케잌 안에 있는 거죠, 그쵸?
Where else would lame Mr. Noballs hide it?
촌뜨기 겁쟁이가 거기말고
또 어디다 숨겼겠어요?
(no balls : 겁쟁이/고환 없는 남자)
나 정말 왜이러는 거죠? 왜 자꾸 계획을
망쳐버리는 건지.. 미안해요. 정말 미안해요.
What's the matter with me?
Why do I keep ruining this?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
아니에요, 내 잘못이에요.
내가 자꾸만 이렇게 바보 같은 방법으로
프로포즈를 하려고 하기 때문이에요.
No, it's my fault
I keep trying to propose in these stupid ways and
all I want to do is tell you that I love you
내가 말하고 싶은 건 단지 내가 당신을 사랑하고, 내 남은 인생을 당신과 보내고 싶다는 것 뿐인데..
and I, I want to spend the rest of my life with you and
지금 할래요.
I'm going to do this now
어머나!
Oh my God!
Phoebe, I... / Wait , wait.
- 피비, 난…
- 잠깐, 잠깐만요.
Oh, no.
아, 아니다.
- 됐어요?
- 네!
Great? / Uh-huh
Phoebe, I love you
피비, 사랑해요.
There's no one else in the world I would ask to marry me
내가 세번 씩이나 결혼해달라고 말할 사람은
피비 당신 밖에 없을 거에요.
Three times
But I want to take care of you,
난 당신을 소중히 여겨주고 싶고, 당신과 아이를 갖고 싶고, 함께 늙어가고 싶어요.
have babies with you
and grow old with you
Phoebe Buffay, will you marry me?
피비 부페이, 나와 결혼해 주겠어요?
Yes
좋아요!
I love you
- 사랑해요.
- 내가 더 많이 사랑해요.
I love you more
그럴 순 없을 거에요.
Not possible
이 여자분은 겁쟁이 부인이 될 거랍니다!
She's going to be Mrs. Noballs
So how's the baby styling business going?
그래, 애기 스타일리스트 사업은
어떻게 되어가고 있니?
잘 안되고 있어. 이건 마치..
사람들이 자기들 애기가 못생겼다는
말을 듣기 싫어하는 거 같아.
Not that great. It's...
it's almost as if people don't want to hear
that their babies are ugly
놀라운데?
That's shocking
Oh, it's Ross
어머, 로스네. 안녕, 로스?
Hey, Ross
Hello, Ross
이봐요, 로스!
He's rude
너무 예의없네!